Abandoned artificial satellites.
（ナレーション）
使い捨てられた人工衛星
Tanks jettisoned from shuttles.
シャトルが切り離したタンク
Refuse generated during
space station construction.
ステーション建造時に出た廃棄物
This vast amount of junk floating in space,
space debris, is a very serious threat.
宇宙に浮かぶ たくさんのゴミ
スペースデブリは
実は とても危険な存在です
This is a story of 2075, a time in which
this space garbage has become a problem.
2075年―
これは 宇宙のゴミが
問題になった時代の物語
（ハチマキの鼻歌）
（ギガルト）
新入り お前はそこで待ってろ
Okay, rookie,
you stay put there.
Are you listening
to me, rookie?
聞こえないのか？ 新入り
（警告音）
（ハチマキ）あっ…
Wait there. Don't go near
the engine until...
（ギガルト）そこで待ってろ
エンジンに近づくのは…
Hey! Rookie!
こら 新入り！
Did you hear a word I said?!
何 勘違いしてんだ おい！
Hey!
何やってんだ ったく…
停止信号ぐらい知っとけ
What do you think
you're doing, damn it?
At least learn your suit's
halt code!
（ハチマキ）あっ…
Stay calm. Just swing
to the right.
（ギガルト）
落ち着け ライトに体を振ればいい
ああっ…
（ギガルト）ええい
無駄に慌てやがって この野郎
You panicked over nothing,
you little bastard...
（警告音）
（ギガルト）くそ！
エンジンと制御計が生きてやがった
Crap, the engine and control
system were still working!
♪～
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
Phase 2
Like a Dream
（ハチマキたち）
ウッ ウッ ウッ ウッ…
ア～ ウッ！
（テレビ音声）どうした～ ウッ！
Six!
（ラビィ）６！
（ハチマキ）来た来た… 来たー！
（テレビ音声）
６が来ました ナンバー６
And our next number is a six!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!!!
Banzai! Banzai!
万歳！ 万歳！
（ラビィ）
やったー やった やった
Huh? Did something happen?
（タナベ）
あっ… 何かあったんですか？
（ハチマキ）
宝くじが当たったんだよ
I won the lottery,
that's what!
Yep! 300 million!
そう ３億！
300 million?!
３億！？
Not just yet.
（ユーリ）まだですよ
（タナベ）え？
But if the next number is a 4, he wins.
（ユーリ）
でも 次に４が出たら３億です
No way!
うそ！
I'm the one who bought
the ticket, Hachi,
ねえねえねえ ハチ
買ってきたのは私だからさ―
...so if you win, I get half!
No, no a quarter is fine!
当たったら半分…
いや ４分の１でいい
I helped out with the luck dance,
so I get some too, right?
（課長）僕も
お祈り手伝ってたんだから―
もらえるよね ねえ？
Um...
あの… ど… どうして
そんな格好なんですか？
W-Why are you
dressed like that?
Wanna join in?
（フィー）あんたもやる？
（タナベ）えっ
They say it's a good-luck charm
that's a sure thing.
（フィー）
よく当たるまじないなんだってさ
で… でも
But I...
Hey, here comes
the last number!
（ハチマキ）
おい ラストナンバーだ
えっ あっ…
（ハチマキたち）
ウッ ウッ ウッ ウッ ウッ…
ア～ ウッ！
Oo.
C'mon, four!
４ 来い！
（課長）４！
Four!
４！
（タナベ）４！
Four!
４！
（一同）ぬあーっ…
And those are
tonight's numbers!
（テレビ音声）こんなん出ました
Aw, man...
（ハチマキ）あーあ 172連敗
かすりもしやがらねえ くそ
172 straight losses.
And partial matches don't
pay anything, either, damn it...
I suppose that half-hearted dance
just won't do the trick.
（ユーリ）やはり
インチキな踊りでは駄目ですね
If you're serious, you should go all-out.
This is supposed to be quite effective.
やるなら もっと本格的に
これなんか
かなり当たるようですよ
Good idea! Do you want
to try that next time?
（課長）
いいね 次 それでやろうか
In that case, please be the
human sacrifice, Chief.
（ユーリ）ああ それでは課長は
いけにえを お願いいたします
Don't make jokes
like that!
（課長）
なっ 冗談は やめてちょうだいよ
Senpai, why are you
playing the lottery?
先輩
宝くじ当てて どうするんですか？
Lay off... It's none
of your concern.
うるせえ お前には関係ない
This bozo's dream
is to buy a spaceship.
こいつ 宇宙船 買うのが夢なのよ
えっ で… でも 宇宙船って
ムチャクチャ高いんじゃ…
B-But aren't spaceships really,
really expensive?
That's why he's playing the lottery!
だから 宝くじ やってんじゃない
あっ そーだ
Hey, that reminds me!
Let me show you
something cool. This is...
いいもん見してやるよ これね…
（ハチマキ）ああっ
What's the problem?
You showed it to us before!
（フィー）何だよ
前は見せてくれただろ？
Yeah, so don't go showing it
without asking!
だからって 勝手に見せんなよ
What is it?
何なんですか？ それ
"Idea Notebook for Acquiring
a Spaceship of My Own."
（ユーリ）
マイ宇宙船 獲得構想ノート
はい？
What?
Hoshino-san filled it with ways
he could get a spaceship.
（ユーリ）星野(ほしの)さんが―
宇宙船を手に入れるための方法を
書きためたものです
Apparently, he had it even before
he joined the company.
（フィー）
入社する前から 持ってたらしいよ
（タナベ）へえ
But Senpai, it's not easy
to win the lottery...
でも 先輩 宝くじって
簡単には当たらないんじゃ
ぐっ… く…
There's lots of different ways.
方法は いろいろあんだよ
社長賞をもらうとかさ
I could get the President's Prize, for instance.
Come on, it's not like you'd
ever be chosen for that.
あのな～
お前が選ばれるわけないだろう？
He's right, Hachi. Besides, the President's
Prize is a life-sized Nora-kun.
そうだよ ハッちゃん
それに 社長賞って
等身大ノーラ君なんだから
ノ…
I-I could also rescue some rich old
geezer who's about to kick the bucket,
ほ… 他にも―
お迎えが来そうな
大富豪のじいさんを助けるとか―
...or marry some
rich old lady, or...
逆玉とか…
Are you the
life-saving type?
人助けって柄？
And marrying rich?
Would anybody ever marry you?
逆玉っていうか
そもそも結婚できるんですか？
くっ… 人間その気になりゃあ
結婚だろうが 宇宙船だろうがよ
If a man puts his mind to it, he can get married
or even buy a spaceship!
So, what else do you have written in there?
Let me see your notebook.
…で 他には
何が書いてあるんです？
見せてくださいよ そのノート
What are you doing here, anyway?!
It's your day off, isn't it?!
お前 何しに来たんだ？
非番だろ？
あっ そうなんですよ
That's right, it is!
You know the
procedure, right?
（ハチマキ）
手順は分かってるよな？
Right. I learned how
in a workshop.
（タナベ）
はい 研修で習いましたから
Okay, try to
back away.
おーし 下がってみろ
Right.
（タナベ）はい
うわあ うわあ…
（ハチマキ）バカ野郎
You moron, you're spinning because you're not
thrusting through your body's center of gravity.
ちゃんと体の中心を射抜かないから
回っちまうんだよ
I'm sorry...!
（タナベ）うっ すいません
You gotta be able to judge something's
center of mass in an instant.
質量の中心を
瞬時に判断できるようになれ
'Cause when you're holding tools or debris, it's
even harder to determine your center of mass.
仕事中は
道具やデブリを抱えて―
重心は
もっと分かりづらくなるんだからな
Y-Yes, sir!
ああっ はい
…というか 止めてくださいよ
Or more to the point,
please stop me!
Of course.
（チェンシン）はい
（タナベ）うっ…
うう…
す…すいません
T-Thank you.
Not at all.
（チェンシン）どういたしまして
Just think of your center of gravity as
somewhere around the pit of your stomach.
重心位置は みぞおち辺りだって
考えておくといいよ
Long time now see,
Cheng-Shin.
（ハチマキ）
久しぶりだな チェンシン
Good to be back, Hachimaki.
ただいま ハチマキ
ようやく入ったんだね 新しい人
I see you've finally got
yourselves a new recruit.
Is he a friend
of yours?
お知り合いですか？
Cheng-Shin and I were hired at the same time.
He works as a pilot in Aerospace Section.
同期入社のチェンシン
航宙課でパイロットやってる
My wings are still clipped, though. I'm not
allowed to carry anything but cargo.
まだ 貨物しかやらしてもらえない
半人前だけどね
It will be 1800 hours momentarily.
ISPV-7 is about to enter nighttime mode,
（アナウンス）間もなく18時です
ISPV-７は
夜時間に入りますので―
...so we ask that all corporate blocks
switch over to internal power sources.
各企業ブロックは
電源切り替えをお願いします
Good for you, you have
a new partner.
（チェンシン）よかったじゃないか
待望の新人さんが入って
Too bad she doesn't have
a lick of talent.
才能のかけらもねえがな
Isn't everyone like that
at first?
初めてなら あんなもんだろ？
Besides, she's cute.
それに かわいい子じゃないか
一生懸命で
I like her enthusiasm.
Girls like that oughta be
secretaries or something.
そういうのは
秘書とか やってりゃいいんだ
Oh, so we agree
that she's cute, then.
おっ かわいいって部分には
同意なんだ
You'll never cut it as a pilot.
Your eyes are terrible.
お前 パイロット失格だな
目が悪い
You can't admit it,
can you?
素直じゃないな
Lay off.
うっせえ
Hey, Hachimaki!
（キース）よう ハチマキ
宇宙船は買えたか？
You buy your spaceship yet?
I hear the Yankees lost.
That makes our records the same.
ヤンキース 負けたってよ
これで同率首位だ
Oh, so I guess you lost
the lottery, huh?
何だ やっぱり外れたのか 宝くじ
Even if I do get a spaceship someday,
I'm never letting you aboard it, you hear me?
宇宙船を手に入れても お前だけは
絶対 乗せてやんねえからな
アハハ 冗談
I'm kidding.
But I will!
（バクティ）俺は乗るぞ
だから ちょっとだけ貸してくれよ
So will you lend me some money?
Playing the ponies again?
また競馬か？
No way! I found a sure thing
in the dog races!
いやあ ドッグレースで
いいのがあってさあ
Hey, what's it gonna be?!
I'm taking the last bets now!
（トモルド）おい どうすんだ？
もう締め切るぞ
Give me a minute!
（バクティ）ちょっと待ってよ
C'mon! Somebody!
Anybody!
（デボン）なあ 誰か 誰か…
Work the night shift for me!
I have a date!
誰か 夜勤 代わってくれよ
デートの約束が
You're just gonna get
dumped again, anyway.
どうせ またフラれるんだろ？
Lend me some money,
and I'll do whatever you want!
（バクティ）
金 貸してくれたら 何でもするぞ
Pipe down back there.
お前は黙ってろ
（ババイヤン）
はーい やもめ男の皆さーん
Step right up,
my widower friends!
I've got some
new goodies!
新作が入りましたよ
Rent or buy,
but cash only, please!
レンタル 買い取り
全て 現金でどうぞ
Save some for me!
俺の分 取っとけよ 俺の分
I'm not taking
any more bets!
（トモルド）こっち 締め切るぞ！
Wait, I want in, too!
Hey, Cheng-Shin! Spot me!
待て待て 俺も入る
おい チェンシン ちょっと貸せ
（チェンシン）はあ？
C'mon, it's a sure thing!
I'll pay you back triple!
大丈夫だって
３倍返しにしてやるから
♪～
（ハチマキ）おっ
I did it!
できた！
先輩 できました！
Senpai, I did it!
Don't get cocky just 'cause
you did it once.
１回できたくらいで喜ぶな
もう１回
Again!
Right!
はい
やった またできた
先輩 できましたよ！
I did it!
I did it again!
Senpai, I did it!
Geez...
ったく… できて当たり前(めえ)だって
Of course you did.
I've been working with you
for days, haven't I?
何日 つきあわせたんだよ
（社員たちの歓声）
あっ
I knew you could do it,
Cheng-Shin!
（バクティ）
さすがだよな チェンシンは
He's had great grades
ever since training!
（デボン）研修の時から
成績 良かったよなあ
Hey, what's the occasion?
（ハチマキ）
よう 盛り上がってるじゃねえか
Cheng-Shin says he's
moved up in the world.
チェンシンが出世したんだってよ
Moved up?
出世？
He's a ship's captain.
（トモルド）船長さまだよ
I said I'm a copilot.
副操縦士だって
They're finally letting me
carry people.
ようやく 人を乗せて
飛べるようになったんだ
They are?
そっか
Okay! Let's have a toast!
To the future captain!
よし 乾杯しようぜ！
未来の船長に
（社員）あっ じゃ
ビール頼みましょうか？
I'll go order
some beer, then!
This is Cheng-Shin we're talking about,
so get us some Shaoxing wine!
（ハチマキ）チェンシンの
祝いなんだから 紹興酒だろ
Um, I don't usually drink that...
That was fast...
Just three years.
早(はえ)えな ３年か
You tryin' to move straight up
to company president?
このまま一気に
社長でも目指すか？
Not really.
ならないよ
僕は木星往還船の船長になるんだ
I want to be
the captain of a ship to Jupiter.
You've been sayin' that for years.
Is Jupiter all that great?
前から言ってたな
そんなに木星が魅力的か？
Yes, you're so great,
Cecille baby!
ジョーン 魅力的！
いとしのジョーン…
When do you
start flying?
いつからなんだ？ 飛ぶの
A week from now,
on the GO-S27.
１週間後の GOS-27
No kiddin'...
そっか 頑張れよ
Well, give it all you got.
I hope you get a spaceship
soon, too, Hachi.
ハチも
早く 宇宙船が手に入るといいな
Y-Yeah, Me, too.
おっ おお そうだな
ハァ…
あっ…
Ship's captain, huh...?
船長か…
Um...
（タナベ）あの… 先輩
つきあわせちゃって すいません
I'm sorry for dragging you
out here with me, Senpai.
I'll practice on my
own from now on.
あとは１人で練習しますから
Huh?
んあ？
Um... The thing is, I think
I can handle it by myself.
（タナベ）
あの… だから １人でも…
Hachimaki!
（キース）ハチマキー
（ハチマキ）あっ
Vega uses that area after 1400 hours, so if
you're gonna keep going, use cargo bay B4.
（キース）ここは
14時から ベガ社が使うからな
続けるなら Ｄ４倉庫にしとけ
Hey, is that him? The idiot who says
he's gonna buy his own ship?
（社員１）おい あいつか？
宇宙船 買うってバカは
Buy a spaceship? Do they get
that kinda pay in Half Section?
（社員２）宇宙船を買う？
半課って
そんなに給料 よかったっけ？
Do they get double the pay
'cause they've only got half the people?
人数半分だから
給料は倍だってか？
（３人の笑い声）
Is something funny,
you bastards?
何か おかしいかよ？
（社員１）あ？
（キース）おい ハチマキ
Hey, Hachimaki...
Is me buying a spaceship
that funny?
（ハチマキ）俺が
宇宙船 買ったら おかしいか？
- Um, senpai...
あの… 先輩
（ハチマキ）
なんとか言ってみろ こら
C'mon, say something!
おかしいに決まってんだろ
Of course it's funny! It's funny to hear a punk
from Half Section deluding himself with dreams.
半課のガキが
夢みてえなこと言ってんなよ
くっ…
あっ おい あっ…
Hey!
（社員１）うっ…
（ハチマキ）夢で悪いか！
What's wrong
with dreams?!
What're you doing, Senpai?
Why are you fighting?
何やってんですか 先輩！
ケンカなんて ええっ！？
（社員３）このガキ！
You punk!
（ハチマキ）ううっ…
（社員３）おっ…
（社員２）ううっ おおっ…
（社員１）ううっ…
（タナベ）あっ 先輩！
Senpai!
I've got you now,
you Half Section bastard!
（社員２）捕まえたぞ 半課野郎
You messed with
the wrong people.
（社員１）
ふざけやがって 食らえ！
Eat this!
（ハチマキ）わあっ…
（社員１）おらおら どうした？
（殴る音）
Not so tough now, are ya?!
（ハチマキ）うわっ うっ うわっ…
（ハチマキ）うわあっ ああ…
ああっ… あっ あっ…
うう うう… あっ あっ…
うわああーっ
Hey, are you okay?
（ギガルト）おい 大丈夫か？
Pull it together, rookie.
You want a spaceship, right?
（ギガルト）
しっかりしろよ 新入り
お前 宇宙船 欲しいんだろ？
Don't rush things.
You can take your time.
焦んなよ ゆっくりでいい
ゆっくり ゆっくりだ
Take your time.
Take your time...
あっ… うっ…
ハァ… ったくよ
Damn it...
Sounds like you've come around.
（ユーリ）
意識が戻ったみたいですね
（ユーリ）具合 どうですか？
How do you feel?
Huh? Fine...
（ハチマキ）あっ… ああ
You were moaning in your
sleep pretty badly.
何か ひどく
うなされてましたが…
It was an old dream.
I was having a bad dream.
昔の夢だよ 嫌な夢 見ちまった
I see. Well, I'm glad
it was just a dream.
（ユーリ）そうですか
夢でよかったですね
何だ？ これ
What the heck
is this?
Oh. Miss Tanabe left some
medicine with me.
ああ タナベさんから薬を
（ハチマキ）あっそ
No kiddin'.
She was very worried
about you.
彼女 とても心配してましたよ
She wouldn't listen to me. She said she'd sit up
with you because she was responsible.
自分が原因だから
看病するって聞かないんです
I sent her away because this
is the men's dorm, though.
ここは男子寮だから
帰らせましたけどね
フン
Who asked her
to butt in?
余計なことを
チェンシン お前はすげえな
Cheng-Shin,
you're amazing.
I...
俺は…
（ハチマキ）
俺は何やってんだろうな 一体
What the hell am I doing
with my life?
（フィー）DBR 0721414
DBR-0720-1414.
As bad luck would have it,
this bird has propellant left in it.
こいつ やっかいなことに
推進剤が残ってるのよね
It started out as an asteroid probe,
so it has excellent evasive capability.
もともと
小惑星の探査機だったから―
回避能力は ずばぬけているし―
And its orbit is retrograde to ours, so even
making a rendezvous is going to be tricky.
軌道が逆行しているから
ランデブーも難しいのよ
Our section tried to recover it
three years ago,
３年前に うちで
回収しようとしたんだけど―
...but an accident caused it thrusters
to fire up, and it got away from us.
Of course, every other company's
attempts have failed so far, too.
まっ よその会社も
今まで 全部 失敗してんだけどね
Wow, this sounds like
it'll be tricky.
へえ ややこしそうですね
Well, we would've preferred to leave it alone, but it's come
into low Earth orbit and has intersected our work orbit.
まあ 放っておいても
よかったんだけど―
低軌道に降りてきて
うちの営業軌道と重なっちゃってさ
Luckily, it hasn't made any
orbital corrections near Earth.
幸い地球の近くでは
一度も軌道変更…
Hachi!
ハチ ユー コピー？
You copy?
ああ
Yeah...
It's the same as
any other run, right?
どうせ いつもと同じだろ
Hachi!
You better shape up!
ハチ！ シャキッとしなさい
Starting today, I'm having Tanabe
participate directly in our missions.
今日からタナベにも ミッションに
直接 加わってもらうんだから―
Set a good example
as her senpai.
先輩として 手本を見せな
She's right!
そうですよ
Show me how
it's done, Senpai!
お願いします 先輩
Hachi, try not to butt heads with other
companies' departments, all right?
ハチ あんまり
よその部署とぶつかるなよ
It makes trouble for me...
私の立場…
（ハチマキ）悪かったよ
- Yeah, sorry about that.
Hey, wait a minute!
（ラビィ）あっ ちょっと待って
ダラララララ… ジャーン！
Ta-dah!
Number A-7777-777!
Ａ組 7777-777番
You can tell it's a lucky number just
by looking! With this baby, we...
見るからにラッキーナンバーだろ？
これなら…
Thanks,
but no thanks.
俺は いいよ
（ラビィ）えっ…
I'm done with
lotto drawings.
宝くじは もういいんだ
（ラビィ）いいって…
"Done"?
H-Hey, Hachimaki! Make sure you pay me back!
I bought this for you!
お… おい ハチマキ！
金はちゃんと払えよ
私が立て替えたんだから！
And for these
apology candies, too!
あと このおわびの菓子代！
Um, Senpai...?
（タナベ）あの… 先輩
I'm no good at EVA work,
but I'm pretty lucky.
私 ＥＶＡは駄目ですけど
運はいいんです
That's what got me into the company.
And a space assignment, too.
だから
この会社にも入れちゃったし―
宇宙勤務だって…
If it's okay with you, why don't we
go buy a lotto ticket together?
よかったら 一緒に
買いに行きませんか？ 宝くじ
Who knows,
maybe we'll win?
ひょっとしたら
当たるかもしれませんよ
Show some spirit, Senpai!
気合い入れてくださいよ 先輩
Is that hachimaki headband
just for show?
このハチマキは飾りですか？
I might be a useless rookie,
but I don't sulk about it!
そりゃあ 私は 使えない
ひよっこかもしれないけど―
だからって ふてくされるなんて
I thought you said you were gonna work
hard until you had your own spaceship!
マイ宇宙船 手に入れるまで
頑張るって言ったじゃないですか
Isn't getting a spaceship
your dream, Senpai?
先輩の夢なんでしょ？ 宇宙船
いいかげんにしろ！
Just give it a rest!
I understand...
It's all clear now.
分かってる もう分かってんだ
A measly debris collector could work for decades
and still not be able to buy a real spaceship.
宇宙船なんてな―
たかだか デブリ屋が
何十年 働いたところで―
本物は買えやしねえってな！
What's changed,
these past three years?
３年で 何が変わった？
I'm still a rank and file employee
and I've got no savings.
俺はいまだに 平社員で貯金もない
I pick up debris
day in and day out,
デブリを拾うだけの毎日で―
...and I still don't have the money to buy one
of these spacesuits, much less a spaceship!
マイ宇宙船どころか
この宇宙服一つ 買う金もねえ！
You'll figure it out
soon enough, too.
お前も そのうち分かるよ
Even if you say you're gonna
make your dreams come true,
夢をかなえるって言ったってな―
...there's some things you can do
and some things you can't!
できることと
できないことがあるんだよ！
GO-S27, this is Bay Control.
（クルー）GOS-27
こちら ディーコントロール
Movement of gantry frame
to final position complete.
ガントリーフレーム
定位置への誘導を完了
Exposure confirmed.
（機長）どうだ？
Status?
Sir. Units A, B, and C,
systems go.
はい ユニットＡＢＣ システムゴー
いつでも発進できます
We can launch
at any time.
Are you feeling nervous?
緊張しているか？
Yes, sir.
はい
That's good. Your cargo this time
is human beings.
それでいい 今度の荷物は人間だ
It's a grave responsibility.
Be as nervous as you can.
責任は大きいぞ
思い切り緊張してやれ
Yes, sir.
はい
Hachimaki, make your approach on the satellite
from the direction of the damaged dish.
（フィー）
ハチマキ 衛星に近づくのは―
ダメージのある
パラボラの方向からお願いね
It looks like its control systems
are half dead.
制御計が
半分 死んでるみたいだから
I know. I'm the one
who smashed the thing.
（ハチマキ）
ああ 俺がぶっ壊したからな
If you know about it, then I'll
leave the cleaning to you.
（フィー）
分かってんなら お掃除よろしく
I copy.
（ハチマキ）アイ コピー
Senpai, about
this debris...
先輩 このデブリのこと…
Yeah, I know
all about it.
ああ よーく知ってるさ
Man, nothing has changed
these past three years.
ほんと
３年前と何も変わっちゃいねえ
Neither one of us...
お前も俺も…
Huh? Did you
say something?
（タナベ）えっ 何ですか？
C'mon, let's get rid
of this damn thing.
とっとと 片づけるぞ
Oh. Right.
（タナベ）あっ はい
Listen, I'll do the basic work.
You just stay out of the way.
（ハチマキ）いいか
基本作業は俺がやるから―
お前は 余計なことはしなくていい
You copy?
ユー コピー？
Huh? I copy.
（タナベ）アイ… アイ コピー
Plus, we're dealing with debris
that has moving parts this mission.
それから 今回のミッションは
動きのあるデブリだ
If you don't wanna get killed by having your
face smashed in, don't open your face guard.
顔をつぶされて死にたくないなら
フェイスガードを開けるなよ
アイ コピー
I copy...
（タナベ）
私 モニター画面 苦手なんですよ
I can't handle watching things
on a monitor screen...
I'm terrible at games
and stuff...
ゲームとか 全然 駄目なんで
（ハチマキ）
俺が制御パネルを抑えるまで―
You stay put over there until
I turn off the control panel.
お前は そこにいろ
Huh? Give me
a minute!
（タナベ）
えっ ちょっと待ってください
Watch out for
the arm.
（ハチマキ）アームに気をつけろよ
（タナベ）アーム？
Arm?
（警告音）
（タナベ）
えっ あっ… ちょっと
H-Hey!
Watch it!
危ない うわあっ！
（ハチマキ）ああっ… 接触警報？
Collision alert?
Crap, she did the
same damn thing I did...
ったく…
俺と同じようなこと やりやがって
Um... Did I do
something wrong?
（タナベ）あ… あの…
何か私 マズかったでしょうか？
Damn it,
that stupid rookie...!
（ハチマキ）くそ 新入りが
Okay, automatic controls
are cut!
よし 自動制御はカット
Hachi, can you bring it back on manual?
You're pretty far out of your predicted orbit.
ハチ 手動で戻せる？
予定軌道から かなりずれてるけど
Yeah, there's propellant left
in the other engine, so I...
（ハチマキ）
ああ もう片っぽのエンジンは―
推進剤が残ってるから…
お… おかしいな
スラッサーが反応しねえ
That's weird...
The thruster's not responding.
It's not? Okay, we'll postpone
the mission and...
そうか
じゃあ ミッションを延期して
（ハチマキ）
待てよ せっかく捕まえたんだ
Hold it! We finally caught this thing, so I'll
use the Fishbone to try to decelerate it.
フィッシュボーンを使って
減速させてみる
In the meantime, I'll go
check out the thruster.
その間に俺は
スラスターを確認しておくから
Understood. Careful, you'll run out
of wire in another 20 seconds.
（フィー）分かった あと20秒で
ワイヤーが伸びきるからね
（ハチマキ）アイ コピー
I copy.
Tanabe, I'm sending Yuri out to you,
so stay put where you are.
（フィー）タナベ
ユーリを向かわせるから―
そのまま そこにいて
（タナベ）はい
Yes, ma'am.
Brace for impact.
衝撃に備えて
Ten.
10 ９ ８ ７ ６
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
５ ４ ３ ２ １ ０
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Zero.
Okay, Hachimaki.
How's the thruster look?
（フィー）ＯＫ ハチマキ
スラスターのほうはどう？
Crap, the antenna dish film is tangled up in it.
This is gonna take a while.
（ハチマキ）くそ パラボラの
フィルムが巻きついてて―
ちょっと 時間かかりそうだな
Yuri, see to
recovering Tanabe.
ユーリ
タナベの回収 頼んだわね
I copy.
（ユーリ）アイ コピー
Fee, I think I can get the
thruster straightened out.
（ハチマキ）フィー
スラスターは なんとかなりそうだ
Okay. That's good.
（フィー）そう よかったわ
（ハチマキ）うわああーっ
What's wrong, Hachi?!
（フィー）どうしたの？ ハチ
（ハチマキ）うわあっ
（フィー）ハチ！
Hachi!
（ハチマキ）あっ ああっ…
I got hit by the wire,
but I'm okay.
ワイヤーにやられたけど
大丈夫 機能は生きてる
My suit's
still functional.
I'm sorry, I didn't catch it
on the monitor.
（フィー）
ごめん モニターできてなかった
There doesn't seem to be much
secondary debris, though.
でも ２次デブリはわずかみたい
That last impact changed
your vector again, so...
今ので ベクトルが
また変わったから あっ…
Oh, no...
This orbit is...
マズい この軌道は…
GO-S27, do you read?
This is Control Section.
（クレア）
GOS-27 聞こえますか？
こちら 管制課です
There is a risk of a near miss with debris
DBR-072-1414 on your flight path.
デブリ DBR 0721414と―
進路上にて
ニアミスする危険が発生
（船長）ん？
（操縦士）何やってんだ？ 半課は
What's Half Section
think they're doing?
What about
an orbit change?
軌道変更を
Is there time? It's coming straight at us,
so our relative velocity is too high.
間に合うか？
逆行で来ているから
相対速度が速すぎる
Deploy debris bumper!
デブリバンパを出せ
はい
Yes, sir!
This is the
pilot speaking.
（機長）
機長より ご案内 申し上げます
We will begin immediate
anti-impact preparations...
当機は ただいまより
大気圏突入に向け―
...to ensure our safety
during atmospheric reentry.
安全を確保するため
対衝撃態勢に入ります
Hachi, get back here ASAP!
You're in the shuttle's orbit!
（フィー）ハチ 早く戻って！
シャトル軌道に侵入してる
Hey, wait a minute...!
I know that shuttle!
（ハチマキ）
ちょっと待てよ このシャトルは…
That's the one that
Cheng-Shin's on!
チェンシンが乗ってるやつだ！
Senpai! Get out of there, Senpai!
（タナベ）
先輩 逃げてください！ 先輩
Losing the mass of one person might...
人間１人分の質量なら…
- Shut up!
（ハチマキ）うるせえ！
だったら シャトルはどうなる？
If I left, what would
happen to the shuttle?!
はっ…
This is one time when running away
or failing isn't an option!
（ハチマキ）今回ばかりは
逃げも負けも許されねえ
許されねえんだよ！
It ain't an option!
But senpai!
The shuttle has bumpers!
（タナベ）
でも先輩 シャトルにはバンパーが
There's no way that it can protect it
from something this big!
（ハチマキ）このサイズを
防ぎきれるわけねえだろ！
Hachi...
ハチ
Damn it, I haven't even gotten
my spaceship yet...
（ハチマキ）ったく… 宇宙船も
まだ手に入れてないってのに
Yuri-san, senpai is gonna...
（タナベ）ユーリさん 先輩は？
All we can do now is have faith
in Hoshino-san's abilities.
（ユーリ）あとは星野さんの技術を
信じるしかありません
GO-S27, this is Entry Approach.
（管制官）GOS-27 こちら
リエントリアプローチ
It's no use! Even if we accelerate,
there's not enough time to raise our orbit!
（機長）駄目だ！ 加速して
軌道を上げる時間が足りない！
We have confirmed a red alert.
Abort reentry corridor.
LTS auto functions
are totally dead...
（ハチマキ）
オート機能は完全に死んでる
So I'll have to do it
by hand, then!
やっぱ 手動でやるしかねえ
Okay, this one's
still online...
よし こいつは生きてる
Fee! Give me a realtime feed of the course
data for the shuttle and the debris!
（ハチマキ）フィー シャトルと
デブリの進路データを―
リアルタイムで
こっちに送ってくれ
（フィー）分かった
Got it.
Here goes...
（ハチマキ）さて…
（深呼吸）
Judging from this remaining propellant,
I've only got one chance.
（ハチマキ）残りの
推進剤からするとワンチャンス
And I have to thrust through the center
of mass of a spinning body, or it's all over.
しかも 回ってるやつの
中心を射抜けなきゃアウトだ
Can I seriously
pull this off...?
やれるかな
マジで
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Can I really
do this...?
（ハチマキ）できるのか？ 本当に
Stay focused...
迷うな まだだ こらえろ
Not yet.
Stay with it...
Just a little more, and its position
will be along the center of gravity...
こいつの位置は もう少しで中心
Those Half Section guys
did that?
（機長）
半課の連中がやったのか
加速して こっちの軌道の上に
It accelerated and moved
into an orbit above ours!
ああ…
（ハチマキ）
フッ フフ ハハハハッ…
Well, I'll be! I actually did it!
何だよ できたじゃないか
See that, Cheng-Shin?
なっ チェンシン
Hoshino-san!
（ユーリ）星野さん
（タナベ）先輩
Senpai!
Are you all right?
（タナベ）大丈夫でしたか？
Oops. Darn it...
…と いっけない
うう うわっ うわあっ…
Hey, rookie, don't be
in such a rush.
（ハチマキ）おいおい
そんなに焦んなよ 新入り
えっ
Sir?
You're just getting started.
まだまだ 始まったばっかりだ
焦んなくていい
There's no rush. Just take your time
and build it up a little at a time.
ゆっくり ゆっくり
積み上げていけばいいって
Am I right?
だろ？
（タナベ）えっ まあ…
Huh? I guess...
Give it three years. Nah, make it five,
and I'll have you whipped into shape.
（ハチマキ）３年… いや
５年もすりゃあ 一人前になるって
Five years, huh...?
（タナベ）５年ですか…
Wait, you didn't see my breathtaking
EVA work, did you? Make it ten!
（ハチマキ）あっ お前
俺の華麗なＥＶＡを見損なったな？
10年だ こりゃ
It just keeps climbing,
doesn't it?
（タナベ）いきなり増えてますね
Um... Who's going to write up
the letter of apology for this one?
（ユーリ）あの… 今回の始末書
誰が書くんでしょうか？
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Return Trajectory
This is our tuition plan. It's a bargain.
（女性１）我が社の
学費プラン お得ですよ
（課長）なんか
入っちゃうんだよねえ
You get dragged in,
don't you?
そ… それって
T-That's a...
It doesn't matter
what I write.
いいんだよ 何だって
えっ…
俺たちの仕事は デブリを
回収するだけだしさ
Our job is to collect debris,
end of story.
My father was a astronaut
through and through.
（女性２）父は
純粋な宇宙飛行士でした
You can't do that!
駄目ですよ そんなの
Damn it, girl,
answer me!
返事ぐらい
しろってんだよ！
Hey!
（ハチマキ）こら！
He should go home
to Earth!
（タナベ）
地球に戻るべきなんです
I'd leave them love!
愛です！
（ハチマキ）お前 バカだ
You're an idiot.